我们希望机器人做的任务是将这根杆的末端定位到尖端
The task that we want the robot to do is to position the end of this rod to the tip of
这根棒，对我来说这是一件相对容易的事情。我用双眼
this rod, and that’s a relatively easy thing for me to do. I’m using both my eyes to
引导我的手，以实现这一特定的动作。但是，如果我只使用一只眼睛
guide my hand in order to achieve that particular motion. However, if I’m only using one eye
存在一些模棱两可的可能性。仅使用一只眼睛，实际上非常困难
there is a potential for some ambiguity. Using just a single eye, it’s actually quite difficult
让我确定沿轴离开我眼睛的距离。为了要达到
for me to determine the distance along the axis away from my eye. In order to achieve
这个定位任务在三个维度上，我实际上需要使用两个摄像头视图和
this positioning task in three dimensions, I actually need to use two camera views and
摄像机需要处于不同的视点。
the cameras need to be at different viewpoints.
这是我们刚看到的问题的简单图形表示。我们
Here is a simple graphical representation of the problem that we just looked at. We
有固定的蓝色物体，我们有移动的红色物体，我们
have the blue object which is fixed, and we have the red object which is moving, and we
想要将红色物体的尖端带到蓝色物体的尖端。这很明显
want to bring the tip of the red object to the tip of the blue object. And this is clearly
在三维空间中发生的任务。现在，考虑我们有一个摄像头观察
a task that occurs in three-dimensional space. Now, consider that we have a camera observing
任务，我们在这里看到相机的视图。我们看到蓝色物体和红色物体。
the task and we see here the camera’s view. We see the blue object and the red object.
因此，当任务完成后，我们会在相机的眼睛视图中看到它的样子，
So when the task is accomplished, we see what it looks like in the camera’s eye view,
并且我们看到在这个二维投影中发生的任务的尖端
and we see that in this two-dimensional projection of the task occurring that the tip of the
红色物体被带到蓝色物体的尖端。所以这个任务正在实现
red object is brought to the tip of the blue object. So the task is being achieved in the
图像以及在三维空间中实现。
image as well as being achieved in three-dimensional space.
它并不那么简单。
It’s not quite that simple.
现在考虑我不正确地执行任务。我将红色物体带到这个位置。现在，
Consider now that I perform the task incorrectly. I bring the red object to this position. Now,
任务尚未实现：红色物体的尖端未达到尖端
the task has not been achieved: the tip of the red object has not met the tip of the
三维空间中的蓝色物体。但在图像平面中，任务看起来像它
blue object in three-dimensional space. But in the image plane, the task looks like it
已经实现了。我们可以说在这个水平方向上，我们可以观察到运动
has been achieved. We can say that in this horizontal direction, we can observe the motion
红色物体。但是在远离相机的方向上，我们无法观察到
of the red object. But in this direction away from the camera, we are unable to observe
物体的运动。
the motion of the object.
所以我们有一个可观察到的自由度，我们有一个不可观察的自由度。
So we have an observable degree of freedom and we have an un-observable degree of freedom.
我们可以考虑这个问题的另一种方法是，使用相机，我们正在进行测量。
Another way we can think about this problem is that with the camera, we are making a measurement.
它是一个测量u，v：图像平面中红色物体的坐标。所以我们已经
It’s a measurement u,v: the coordinate of the red object in the image plane. So we’ve
有两个测量。我们正在测量两个数字，u和v。然后我们的任务发生在
got two measurements. We are measuring two numbers, u and v. Then our task occurs in
三维空间：我们的任务有三个自由度。所以两次测量
three-dimensional space: our task has got three degrees of freedom. So two measurements
不足以完成三个自由度的任务。
is insufficient to achieve a task with three degrees of freedom.
现在，让我们考虑一下，我们用两台看看任务的相机来执行此操作
Now, let’s consider that we perform this with two cameras having a look at the task
这已经完成了。这些相机有不同的观点。所以，如果我们表演
that’s being accomplished. These cameras have got different viewpoints. So if we perform
一项任务，我们现在可以看到它在每个摄像机视图中的外观。这一次，任务正在进行中
a task, we can now see how it looks in each camera view. This time, the task is being
实现正确。现在，我们正在对正在发生的事情进行四次测量。我们是
achieved correctly. Now, we are making four measurements about what’s going on. We are
在一台相机中测量u和v。我们用另一台相机测量u和v。现在，我们已经
measuring u and v in one camera. We are measuring u and v with another camera. Now, we’ve
得到四次测量，这足以完成三个自由度的任务。
got four measurements, and that is sufficient to achieve a task with three degrees of freedom.
因此，为了完成任务，测量次数必须大于或等于
So in order to achieve a task, the number of measurements must be greater than or equal
到自由度的数量。
to the number of degrees of freedom.
很久以前，我们实际上建立了一个真正的机器人系统来做到这一点。现在，任务是
A long time ago, we actually built a real robot system to do this. Now, the task was
将此处所示的工具插入地下采矿顶部的孔中
to insert a tool, which is shown here, in to a hole in the roof of an underground mining
隧道。机器人工具尖端的每一侧都有一个摄像头，它正在观察
tunnel. There is a camera on each side of the robot’s tool tip and it’s observing
屋顶上的洞;你可以看到这里显示为绿色区域。那是什么
the hole in the roof; and you can see that shown here as the green region. And what the
控制系统正在做的是将工具的尖端带到绿色区域的中心
control system is doing is to bring the tip of the tool to the centre of the green region
同时在两个摄像头视图中。如果它这样做，则意味着隐含
simultaneously in both camera views. And if it does that, then it means that implicitly
该工具已被放入采矿隧道顶部的洞中。
the tool has been put in to the hole in the roof of the mining tunnel.
让我们回顾一下基于视觉的控制与传统机器人控制之间的区别。
Let’s recap on the difference between vision-based control and conventional robot control.
在传统的机器人控制中，观察机器人的末端执行器的姿势
In conventional robot control, the observation of the pose of the robot’s end effector
是间接的。我们使用测量关节角度的传感器，我们使用运动学
is indirect. We use sensors that measure the angles of the joints, and we use a kinematic
用于计算机器人末端所在位置的模型。所以这只是推断。
model to compute where the end of the robot is. So it is just inferred.
我们还需要告诉对象在笛卡尔空间中的位置，然后是任务
We also need to be told the position of the object in Cartesian space and then the task
控制器的作用是将机器人末端执行器的推断位置带到
of the controller is to bring the inferred position of the robot’s end effector to
我们事先知道的物体的位置。
the position of the object which we know in advance.
相反，基于视觉的控制是直接观察工具和物体，
Vision-based control by contrast is direct observation of the tool, and of the object,
以及这两件事之间的错误。在基于视觉的控制中，我们尝试并开车
and of the error between those two things. In vision-based control, we try and drive
该错误为零。我们实际上并不知道对象的姿势。我们实际上并没有
that error to zero. We don’t actually know the pose of the object. We don’t actually
知道机器人工具的姿势。我们只是观察错误并将其驱动为零。
know the pose of the robot’s tool. We simply observe the error and drive that to zero.
这种技术通常称为视觉伺服。
This is a technique that’s commonly called visual servoing.
视觉伺服有许多潜在的用途。例如，在制造业务中，
There are many potential uses of visual servoing. For instance, in a manufacturing operation,
我们可能需要拾取随机放置在传送带上的物体。视觉伺服
we may need to pick up objects that are randomly placed on a conveyor belt. Visual servoing
可以引导机器人的尖端在它们移动过去时拾取这些物体。它
could guide the tip of a robot to pick up these objects as they are moving past. It
也可以用来抓住在架空传输线上摆动的物体
could also be used to grab objects which are swinging on an overhead transfer line for
例。它可以用于交配任务，也许可以将加油喷嘴放入汽车，
example. It could be used for a mating task, perhaps to put fueling nozzle in to a car,
进入航天器或飞机。
into a spacecraft, or an aircraft.
考虑像水果采摘这样的问题。我们不知道每个的x，y和z位置
Consider a problem like fruit picking. We don’t know the x, y, and z location of every
苹果在果园里。也许，我们甚至不知道机器人的位置
apple in the orchard. Perhaps, we don’t even know the location of the robot within
果园。但是使用这种视觉控制策略，机器人可以伸出并减少
the orchard. But using this visual control strategy, a robot can reach out and reduce
其工具提示与苹果之间的误差为零。在这种情况下，它已经实现了
the error between its tool tip and an apple to zero. In which case, then it has achieved
掌握那种水果，可以把它从树上取下来。
a grasp of that fruit and can remove it from the tree.
我们可以考虑将飞机降落在跑道上的问题。我们观察跑道。
We could consider the problem of landing an aircraft on a runway. We observe the runway.
我们可以看到一些非常明显的视觉特征：一些漂亮的白线，一些漂亮的白色
We can see some very obvious visual features there: some nice white lines, some nice white
矩形，我们可以用它来控制飞机，使其高度超过
rectangles, and we could use those to control the aircraft so that its height above the
跑道在与跑道对齐时变为零。
runway becomes zero while being aligned with that runway.
它可以用于将水下机器人保持在固定的位置，尽管有海洋
It could be used for keeping an underwater robot at a fixed location despite an ocean
目前试图将其从想要的地方推开。它可以用来指导
current trying to push it away from where it wants to be. It could be used to guide
水下机器人跟随水下管道。它可以用于像
an underwater robot following an underwater pipeline. It could be used for tasks like
杂耍等等。基于视觉的控制的应用几乎是无限的。
juggling and so on. The applications of vision-based control are almost limitless.